Muhammad Tanweerul ISLAM

Mobile: +880 17 4930 9273 Email: tanweerul87@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Profile Portfolio e-Profile

SUMMARY

I am an accountant with a multi-faceted background encompassing Australian, South Asian and Middle Eastern cultures; who has valuable experience in accounts payable including raising/creating purchase requisitions & purchase orders, product receipting, posting corporate invoices and statement reconciliation, using Microsoft Dynamics 365. I can prepare financial statements, analyze financial data and manage audit files, using integrated excel spreadsheets with accounting software, from a previous internship. I truly value the responsibility of serving the society and I can do this by contributing towards the integrity of accounting systems as set out by the international accounting standards.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

As an enthusiastic accountant, I seek a job placement where I can apply my accounting experience along with analytical skills and knowledge.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Result-oriented
- Client-oriented
- Self-motivator

- Team player
- Multitasker
- Effective written & oral communication skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Experienced in ERP System Microsoft Dynamics 365 (Accounts Payable)
- Experienced with regular software applications (MS Office Suite, MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel V look
 up and pivot tables, MS Outlook)
- Experienced in accounting software (MYOB, XERO)
- Experienced with Windows & Mac operating systems

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

The Arnhem Land Progress Aboriginal Corporation (ALPA) (Darwin, Australia)

May 2019 – September 2019

ALPA started as a co-operative of community stores and currently operates various local businesses in partnership with local communities developing jobs and training programs. ALPA is one of the largest independent employers of aboriginal people in Australia with a turnover of approximately \$75 million across the group.

TRAINEE FINANCE OFFICER

August 2019 - September 2019

I was affiliated with the finance team to look after seven ALPA stores which involved numerous account payable responsibilities.

Key Duties & Responsibilities:

- Developed a procedure to streamline the reconciliation process of supplier statements for seven ALPA stores.
 The procedure included tracing missing invoices, confirmation of goods received in each store and using accounting software (D365, CLICK invoicing and Finance Manager) to ensure accurate data collection
- Raising purchase requisition and purchase orders, product receipting and posting corporate invoices using the ERP system Microsoft Dynamics 365 (D365)
- Organizing ALPA finance email inbox to allocate emails to appropriate finance team members

<u>Team Building Activity</u>: Participated in a team building activity - The Survivor, where my team was announced as the winner.

FINANCE INTERN

May 2019 - July 2019

I was affiliated with the finance department and involved in numerous accounting engagements as part of a team that catered to ALPA stores.

Key Duties & Responsibilities:

- Testing of ERP system which included accounts receivables, accounts payables, cash/bank management, general ledger, budgets and workflow processes which required thorough study of D365 manuals
- Developed and maintained a system of spreadsheets in Microsoft Excel to track stock invoice movements on a daily basis
- Developed freight invoicing manual for ALPA
- Supplier statement reconciliation of seven ALPA stores
- Correspondence with vendors and stores via email and telephone to ensure a smooth communication process

RABIN & ASSOCIATES (Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia)

March 2014 - August 2014

Rabin & Associates is a well-established reputed firm offering audit, accounting, tax and advisory services in Malaysia and abroad.

AUDIT INTERN

I was affiliated with the audit department and involved in numerous accounting and auditing engagements either as part of a team that catered to big clients, or by myself attending to smaller, more dormant clients.

Key Duties & Responsibilities:

- Physical performance verification to documents
- Preparation and proper documentation of audit working papers in compliance to audit and statutory requirements using Excel & MYOB
- Preparation of formal audit report to express an opinion on the financial statements
- Industries covered: Medical services, marketing, trading and investment holding

Professional Membership: Golden Key International Honor Society

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

MODHUR CANTEEN (Sydney, Australia)

September 2017 – June 2018

- Cashier & Customer Service: This designation involved cash handling; electronic funds transfer at point of sale (EFTPOS) & customer service.
- Achievements & Contributions: Efficient at EFTPOS and opening/closing cash tills. Additionally, I was tasked with
 maintaining a logbook and ensuring an elevated standard of customer service with an exceptional dining
 experience.

7 ELEVEN (Sydney, Australia)

November 2016 - April 2017

- Retail Assistant: I was in charge of providing customer service & inventory management.
- Achievements & Contributions: Efficient at electronic funds transfer at point of sale (EFTPOS) and opening/closing cash tills. I also contributed to a pleasant experience for visiting customers.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

British Council (Chittagong, Bangladesh)

January 2006 - June 2006

- Completed Ordinary Level (O-Level)
 - Accounting
 - o Bengali
 - Economics
 - English Language
 - Mathematics

British Council (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

January 2009 - June 2009

- Completed Advanced Level (A-Level)
 - Accounting
 - Business Studies
 - Mathematics

Multimedia University (MMU) (Cyberjaya, Malaysia)

February 2010 - October 2014

Completed Bachelor in Accounting (Honors) with CGPA 3.01

University of New South Wales (UNSW) (Sydney, Australia)

February 2015 – February 2016

Master of Professional Accounting (Ext)

Charles Sturt University (CSU) (Sydney, Australia)

March 2016 - November 2017

Completed Master of Professional Accounting (MPA) with GPA 4.44

Navitas Professional (Darwin, Australia)

September 2018 - July 2019

Professional Year Program (Accounting)

VOLUNTARY WORK

Golden Key International Honor Society (MMU Chapter)

Literacy Service & Outreach Director

I was associated with the event management and networking team. Throughout this period, I participated in numerous projects and volunteered as part of the team.

General Responsibilities:

- Involved developing, promoting, and maintaining a wide range of literacy-focused volunteer opportunities that
 positively impacted the Cyberjaya community
- Recruited a diverse cadre of team members to assist in literacy projects and programs
- Ensured real-time tracking of progress towards program outcomes against set goals
- Attended literacy-focused volunteer projects to ensure meaningful volunteer experiences for participants
- Executed volunteer outreach and communication strategies via email, telephone and social media

Cyberjaya Accounting Club (CAC)

Secretary & Event Management Team Member

I was incorporated with the Association of Chartered Certified Accountant (ACCA), where I did volunteer work as a secretary. I also played a key role as a team member in the event management division and assisted the team with events related to the career fair.

General Responsibilities:

- Attended club meetings and recorded meeting minutes
- Worked as an usher and ensured seating arrangements adhered to standards and regulations
- Maintained a clean and organized event hall
- Guaranteed excellent standards of customer service
- Utilized social media to communicate with guests and staff

Red Crescent Society (MMU Chapter)

Chapter Member

I volunteered in a disaster relief workshop organized by the Red Crescent Society of MMU, where I was formally trained to think critically, and effectively communicate using radio frequency in times of emergency. The workshop also provided First Aid and Cardio-Pulmonary Resuscitation (CPR) tutorials and sessions for social interactions during emergency situations.

LANGUAGE

English: Fluent
Bengali: Fluent
Hindi: Basic
Urdu: Basic

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

• Creative Writing: Poetry, rap and short stories

Movies: Mystery, thriller, romance and comedy

• Music: EDM, R&B and hip-hop

Cooking: Bengali, Indian, Thai and Italian cuisines
 Sports: Cricket, table tennis, billiard and badminton

• **Documentaries:** Aviation, automobile, architecture, food, travel and life style

• Photography: Landscape, portrait, still life, black & white, candid, cityscape, food, travel, lifestyle and street

REFERENCES

Reference on request